<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Engineering on aonemd</title>
    <link>https://aonemd.github.io/categories/software-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Engineering on aonemd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aonemd.github.io/categories/software-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bear Programming</title>
      <link>https://aonemd.github.io/posts/bear-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonemd.github.io/posts/bear-programming/</guid>
      <description>According to Wikipedia, Pair Programming is an agile software development technique in which two programmers work together at one workstation.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a term I call Bear programming that is not the opposite of pair programming. Bear programming is when a team of programmers that work together on a single project starts mauling the code and ripping its different parts apart like a group of bears.
Let me clear this. The mauling here refers to writing code that is distinguishable to the code written by other team members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One Year Old Bug</title>
      <link>https://aonemd.github.io/posts/the-one-year-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aonemd.github.io/posts/the-one-year-bug/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been revisiting my old repositories on GitHub recently to make sure they are still relevant and to clean up the code. One of the projects I looked into was margopher which I started back in August 2015. I only removed some unused code, and updated the README page after which I decided to follow the usage instructions just to make sure everything was okay. This was when I found out that when I created and used a margopher object one time, I could not use it any more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
